Science Fiction Writers of America (SFWA) Records
Science Fiction Writers of America (SFWA) Records
1966-1970
Science Fiction Writers of America
1.5 linear ft.
Correspondence, mailings, organization records and publications of the Science Fiction Writers of America. Includes considerable correspondence from and to Roger Zelazny, Anne Mccaffrey, and Poul Anderson while performing work for the organization.
149572
Biographical History
The Science Fiction Writers of America (SFWA), founded in 1965 by Damon Knight and now known as the Science Fiction and Fantasy Writers of America, is a nonprofit organization of professional science fiction writers in the United States. The purpose of the SFWA is to inform, support, promote, defend and advocate for both its members and the genre. SFWA activities include informing science fiction and fantasy writers on professional matters, protecting their interests, and helping them deal effectively with agents, editors, anthologists, and producers in media; encouraging public interest in and appreciation for science fiction and fantasy literature; and sponsoring, editing, and disseminating writings, papers, and other publications which exemplify science fiction and fantasy literature of high quality.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Science Fiction Writers of America (SFWA) Records consists of correspondence subject files, organizational records and publications.
Correspondence subject files consists of questionnaires given to writers and editors on the science fiction genre, mailings to and from the SFWA, correspondence to and from the secretary-treasurer of the SFWA for the years 1967-1970, the secretary-treasurer handbook, secretary-treasurer records and materials 1967-1968. This series also contains correspondence, drafts, proofs and selection information for the 4th Nebula Anthology as well as information concerning the 4th Nebula Awards Banquet.
Organizational records contains the organization's bylaws as of 1966, SFWA copyright information for 1966-1967, and financial records from 1966-1970.
Publications contains general publications from the SFWA, copies of the SFWA Bulletin from August 1967-February 1969, copies of the SFWA Forum from October 1967-February 1970, and copies of assorted other science fiction publications.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is arranged alphabetically by type. Material within each series is arranged alphabetically and then further arranged chronologically if applicable.
Related Material
has the papers and collections of a number of science fiction writers and publishers. Please refer to for a complete listing.
has extensive holding of published material relating to science fiction, including books, periodicals, pulp magazines, fanzines and conference proceedings. Please search search for these related materials.
Subject and Genre Headings
Popular culture; Science fiction; Anderson, Poul, 1926-2001.; McCaffrey, Anne.; Zelazny, Roger.; Science Fiction Writers of America.; Popular culture -- United States.; Popular literature -- United States.; Science fiction, American -- Information resources.; Science fiction, American -- Periodicals.; Science Fiction and Fantasy Writers of America; Correspondence.; Financial records.; Printers' proofs.; Publications (documents); Questionnaires.; Authors.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Science Fiction Writers of America, 1966-1970, 1973.
Inventory
- Correspondence subject files
  - Double-Bill symposium questionaire, 1963; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Farrar, Straus and Giroux correspondence, 1 Aug 1966 (Box 1)
  - Mailings (Box 1)
  - Nebula anthology (4th)
    - Correspondence, 1968-1969; from and to Poul Anderson, concerning anthology (Box 1)
    - Drafts (Box 1)
    - Proofs, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Selection Process (Box 1)
  - Nebula awards (4th) banquet, Invitation, topics, voting ballot (Box 1)
  - Secretary-Treasurer
    - Correspondence, 1967; 2 folders; from and to Roger Zelazny (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1968-1970; 4 folders; from and to Roger Zelazny, Anne McCaffrey (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, undated (Box 2)
    - Handbook (initial draft) (Box 2)
    - Handbook (Box 2)
    - Records/materials, 1967-1968; notes, mailings, application forms, reports (Box 2)
- Organizational records
  - Bylaws, 1966 (Box 2)
  - Copyrights, Aug 1966-Sep 1967 (Box 2)
  - Financial records, 1966-1968; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Financial records, 1969-1970 (Box 3)
- Publications
  - General, importance of criticism, mental illness and its connection with science fiction (Box 3)
  - SFWA Bulletin, Aug 1967-Feb 1970; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - SFWA Forum, 1967-1970 (Box 3)